注：Secret Informant意思是秘密线人，但是内容都是美食
Hong Kong is inherently a fusion of cultures originally a largely
香港是一个诸多外来文化的结合体
最初很少人居住的香港 在十九世纪中期
注：中文字幕和英文字幕是官方字幕，未经过修改，但是时间轴没对齐
uninhabited region of China the Qing Dynasty ceded it to Britain in the
被清朝政府割让给英国作为不列颠王国殖民地
注：旁白是techlinked的Riley，本视频上传于20180810
mid-1800s who developed it into a major commercial center before handing it back
在1997年回归中国之前的一百多年里
香港已经蓬勃发展成了世界皆知的经济贸易中心
to China in 1997 a hundred and fifty years of Eastern and Western influences
在中西文化相互交融的一百五十年里
mingling together have produced a distinctive culture which celebrates
香港发展出了自己独特的本地文化
这种传统结合现代与未来的独特文化
tradition but also looks to the future that spirit of innovation can be seen
在这家位于香港市中心的李好味餐厅里得以完美诠释
quite clearly at lilo may wear classic recipes are given a modern twist our
他们在香港传统菜的制作上巧妙地结合了现代制作工艺
今天带我们来见证道地厨艺的本地向导 Stanley
guide to this new culinary landscape Stan Lee talks to the brains behind lilo
与李好味的主厨 Max Lee 做了一次深入交流
maze reinvention of Hong Kong staples local chef, Max Lee.
大家好 我是 Max 我做厨师已经有15年了
这家餐厅的菜色是亚洲文化的结合
我们坚持使用香港本地的食材
这道黄金虾球 我们加入了许多材料
用了中国传统的食材像是咸蛋黄
这白色的底酱是用花菜做的
你知道咸蛋黄会比较油腻
所以花菜泥就能很好地平衡一下
我们用牛颊肉作为这道料理的原料
牛颊肉要慢慢烧
然后我们用中式烹饪方式料理牛筋
最后装盘时配上西式土豆泥
我们这里的当家料理 李小龙虾
是在烤架上制作完成的
会配上新加坡辣椒酱
加上银丝卷配炼乳
这样就有两个蘸酱 一个鲜 一个甜
感谢你给我们详细地介绍了这样一个独特的地方
感谢你们的光临
我觉得我有点穿着不得体
我们在拍摄了你头上还戴着墨镜
that's kind of like my that's my thing you know I'm the shades guy you're
我是戴墨镜的男人
the you have a guy with the shades yeah why don't you walk us through your
这倒是我的风格
Stanley 能麻烦你给我们简单介绍一下么
Stanley what are we looking at yes okay so on our right
右手边的这道是黄金虾球
basically fried shrimp coated in salted egg yolks
oh my yes and at the bottom you can also see there's some white cauliflower puree
在虾球底下铺着的是一层白色的花菜泥
Wow yeah really we just grab one of these yeah I don't know you're just
是么 就这么夹起来么
我们就这么开吃了
going we're going for it straight into it no more talking Wow
废话不多 直接开吃
that's it at the flower oh they had truffle to it as well
他们有在花菜泥里加入松露
里面有加松露哦
that's actually gonna funny because it like I almost there's definitely a
怪不得我尝到里面有一种我没法很好形容的好吃的东西
quality quality to it that I couldn't really describe and that kind of makes
现在知道是什么了
sense now that's like prawn tempura with a million layers added to it and like
就像是天妇罗加上了上百种美味
way better I don't know what it is but it's kind of grainy which is a texture I
我不知道这种粉粉的口感是什么
didn't think I was gonna get so today I love salted it like visually you can see
这是咸蛋黄 我超喜欢咸蛋黄
光是看着就知道这道菜里加入了很多独特的配方
how much flavour and how much how many extra things are added to make this like
a really interesting taste experience lobster lobster how do we even begin to
龙虾
我们应该怎么开动呢
approach this this is kind of a fusion thing right here correct and you can see
这明显是一道融合了各种料理精华的集合体
可以看到这表面是黑椒酱
the sauce here is actually black pepper sauce oh yeah yeah this is the deep
这道是油炸银丝卷
fried of Chinese buns and they used to go with that
银丝卷一般是和炼乳一起吃的
right but the condensed milk here is actually padded into Seoul again so you
不过这里的炼乳被打成泡沫状了
所以吃一口龙虾要马上跟银丝卷
eat lobster and then you chase it like alcohol you just chase it down whoa
嗯 差不多
就像猛喝一口酒之后马上跟饮料一样
第一口吃到的是类似烤肉酱的味道
okay well the very first thing I tasted was kind of like a barbecue sauce but
这酱料和精心制作的龙虾结合的很好
then that kind of like sort of kind of melted into like what you would think of
a traditional lobster curry tastes like kind of like that buttery smooth
龙虾的口感油滑 甜润 还有一些淡淡的烟熏味
sweetness I guess the smokey would be the right description oh my goodness I'm
我的天哪
like a really warm campfire my tummy okay now this is just like a chaser I
我感觉肚子里有一股温暖的感觉 像是黑夜里的营火
紧接着我们要跟银丝卷
want to Lover's I'm gonna versus Plitt break the bread with you oh ah there you
一人一半 感情不散
跟你分面包吃
啊 分开了
go what do you want for the black pepper
你要怎么吃
我先试试蘸黑椒酱吃
okay right I'm gonna go in front of the condensed milk I think I'm gonna do the
我就直接上炼乳了
我也来试试炼乳
condensing okay you know what we'll meet back in the middle hey oh oh okay oh
往中间这样挤上来
it's like a doughnut it's not like crazy crunchy it's just like kind of crisp the
这不就是甜甜圈么
并不是整个都很有嚼劲 而是表皮被炸得脆脆的
内部口感很松软 很轻盈
inside is like super super fluffy and light yeah like it's almost like it
感觉简直像是不存在一样
doesn't exist by the way I loved foam condensed oh yeah I don't know if they
我超喜欢这个炼乳泡
不知道这是不是和其他的什么材料混合在一起
mix it with anything but it also seems like it like the sweetness has to come
只是吃起来没有普通炼乳那么甜
down a little bit so it's just more of a em
是有一点哦
更加是一种温柔恬静的甜味
probably legs weakness a quiet sweet quiet sweetness so far this is a two out
恬静的甜味吼
现在三道菜里的两道菜都很好味
of three knocking it out of the park yeah
so again if I've got high expectations for dish number three and then to tell
我告诉你 我现在对第三道菜超级期待的
ya if it lets me down it'll still be a great day so this is
就算这道菜让我失望了
前面吃的两道菜还是让我非常满足
这道菜叫猛牛三争霸
called a beef trio as with beef cheek beef tendon and the mash that's the trio
有牛颊 牛筋 还有土豆泥 三样
very cool Wow that chops that went through that with ease so this is the
好棒棒
筷子就这么捅进肉里了 没阻力
there's a bit of mustard mash down there to that you got a pick up so mustard
搅一点芥末在里面
这就变成了芥末泥
mesh it's it it was a mustard mash go parliament
吃
oh that's not the texture I was expecting at all you bite into it and
完全没有意料到会是这种口感
咬下去口感有点像果冻却有点黏黏的
it's it is kind of like a jello but it's a lot more sticky and it gives a lot
让它嚼起来有一点阻力
more resistance yeah yeah oh I can do it someone's like a dough also I got I got
是啊是啊是啊
有点像是在嚼面团
再加入一些土豆芥末泥
a little bit of the mustard mashed potatoes is that just like mashed
这个就只是土豆泥和第戎芥末酱拌在一起么
potatoes and Dijon mustard I might start doing this if I want to be a bit more
我以后要试试看这么做豪华土豆泥
fancy it's my money and I'm not but they those that is so good
这个好好吃
that's really interesting now I'm a German I'm from a German and Irish
这个味道很有趣
我有德意志和爱尔兰的血统
ancestry there's lots of potatoes there there's lots of potatoes there and
我的祖先把土豆作为主食
又来了 又开始念祖宗了
我吃过很多土豆做的菜
that's a that is an addition that I have never tried and it is so good okay now
这个超好吃的版本今天是第一次尝到
好吧 现在我们尝尝这个牛颊
we're going onto this cheek onto the cheek
上脸了
see now I'm excited because I actually put the mashed potatoes on my cheek wow
我来把土豆芥末泥抹在牛夹肉上 好期待
wow wow wow it just falls right apart it just like gives away I was fan tastic
下巴一动就碎了 肉好酥哦
太好吃了
Stanley you've done it again by George Stanley you come by Joel I think he's
Stanley 你做得好
done it hey I don't know what cheers Cheers you already took the sentence the
way Cheers it's done